Nathaniel Alexander Owings Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings File, 1944-1977 (Box 44-56)
  - Speeches
    - 1964
      - 25 Apr., California State Polytechnic College, San Luis Obispo, Calif.
      - 24 July, Assembly Committee on Natural Resources Impact of Highways and Freeways on Park Values, Arcata, Calif.
      - 1 Oct., Monterey Savings and Loan Association, Monterey, Calif.
      - 13 Nov ., Museum of Modern Art, New York, N.Y. (Box 54)
      - 8 Dec., Governor's Conference on Good Design, Sacramento, Calif.
    - 1965
      - 12 Jan., San Francisco Planning and Urban Renewal Association annual planning conference, San Francisco, Calif.
      - 21 Jan., "Pennsylvania Avenue and the Future of the American City"
      - 16 Feb., Wayfarers Club, Chicago, Ill.
      - 8-10 Dec., Action Council for Better Cities, Washington, D.C.
      - 21 Dec., Commercial Club, Chicago, Ill.
    - 1966
      - 21 Mar., Rock, Sand, and Gravel Producers Association, San Francisco, Calif.
      - 30 Mar., Mayor's Conference on Urban Design, Kansas City, Mo.
      - 25 Apr., Religious Architecture Conference, San Francisco, Calif.
      - 21 Sept., Scenic Highway dedication at Bixby Bridge, Big Sur, Calif.
      - 7 Oct., Howard University, Washington, D.C.
      - 14 Nov., 62nd National Audubon Convention, Sacramento, Calif.
    - 1967
      - 6 Feb., Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colo.
      - 1 Apr., Architects and Engineers Forum, Los Angeles, Calif.
      - 15 Apr., Washington Gallery of Modern Art, Washington, D.C.
      - 19 Apr., Committee for Downtown, Baltimore, Md.
    - 1968, 24 Sept., Citizens Planning and Housing Association, Baltimore, Md. (Box 55)
    - 1969
      - 22 Jan., Junior League of Palo Alto, Calif.
      - 25 Feb., AIA of New York, Museum of Modern Art, New York, N.Y.
      - 10 Mar., Washington Building Conference, Washington, D.C.
      - 20 Mar., St. Louis University, St. Louis, Mo.
      - 27 Mar., Rice University, Houston, Tex.
      - 10 Apr., Ford Foundation, Santa Barbara, Calif.
      - 15 Apr., Los Angeles, Calif.
      - 17 Apr., American Society of Civil Engineers convention, Louisville, Ky.
      - 25 Apr., Historic Savannah Foundation, Savannah, Ga.
      - 28 Apr., Contemporary Club, Indianapolis, Ind.
      - 7-8 May, Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass.
      - 23-25 Nov., United States National Commission for UNESCO, San Francisco, Calif. (Box 56)
      - 5 Dec., AIA of British Columbia, Vancouver, B.C.
    - 1972
      - 7-9 Feb., White House Conference, Washington, D.C.
      - 3-5 Apr., Walter Prescott Webb International Symposium, University of Texas, Austin, Tex.
      - Oct., "Alice in Wonderland," Des Moines, Iowa
      - 15 Nov., "Through the Looking Glass," University of California, Berkeley, Calif.
      - 20 Nov., Governor's 5th Conservation Congress, Portland, Oreg.
    - 1973, 25 July, CBS Morning News interview
    - 1974, 25 Feb.-2 Mar., AIA annual meeting, San Francisco, Calif.
    - 1976
      - 3 May, AIA College of Fellows, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - 12 Oct., Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y.
    - Undated, "Humanizing Private Development"
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1975, undated
- Miscellany, 1911-1976 (Box 56-59)
  Postcards, printed matter, awards and certificates, bills and receipts, cards and invitations, speeches and writings by authors other than Owings, appointment calendars, and architectural drawings and diagrams.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Appointment calendars (Box 56)
  - Architectural drawing and diagrams See also Oversize
  - Awards and certificates See also Oversize
  - Bills and receipts
  - Cards and invitations
  - Metropolitan Club (Box 57)
  - Military and international driving permits
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Notes and other items
  - Poems
  - Postcards
  - Printed matter
    - Articles
    - Books and booklets, (1 folder)
    - Books and booklets, (1 folder) (Box 58)
    - Pamphlets and brochures, (2 folders)
    - Periodicals and other items
  - Scrapbooks, 1936-1970 See Oversize, (2 vols.) (Box 59)
  - Speeches and writings by others
  - Wayfarers' Club, Chicago, Ill.
- Addition, 1929-1983 (Box 60-64)
  Correspondence received and sent and miscellany including biographical material, speeches and writings, legal and financial papers, minutes and reports, photographs, printed matter, and clippings.
  Organized alphabetically by type of material.
  - Correspondence (Box 60)
    - 1945, 1963-1978, (9 folders)
    - 1979
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 61)
    - 1980-1983, (8 folders)
    - Undated
  - Miscellany (Box 62)
    - Biographical file, 1962-1978, undated
    - Contribution lists, 1968-1977
    - Financial papers, 1975-1979, undated
    - General, 1972-1983, undated
    - Grant applications, 1979-1980
    - Hopi Indian exhibit, Field Museum of Natural History, Chicago, Ill., 1980-1981
    - Kachina dolls, 1973-1978
    - Legal papers, 1971-1979, undated
    - Memberships, 1968-1979, undated
    - Passport, 1973-1978
    - Photographs, 1929-1930, 1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 63)
    - Printed matter, 1958-1983, undated, (3 folders)
    - Printed matter, 1958-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 64)
    - Reports
      - Big Sur Coast Development, Feb. 1980
      - Cornell University Summer Field School, Rome, Italy, 1979
    - Schedules, 1978-1979
    - Speeches, 1983
    - Writings
      - Owings, Nathaniel Alexander
        - 1972, "A Song of Action"
        - Undated, "The Hopi Way"
      - Others, 1971-1983, undated
- Oversize, 1936-1975 (Box OV 1-OV 12)
  Oversize material consisting of scrapbooks, awards and certificates, architectural charts and diagrams, photographic proof sheets and layouts for Owings's book The American Aesthetic, and a copy of a publication sponsored by the President's Temporary Commission on Pennsylvania Avenue, entitled The Washington Mall Master Plan.
  Organized and described according to the series, folders, and boxes from which the items were removed.
  - Subject File (Box OV 1)
    - Monterey coast master plan
      - Scrapbooks
        - 1959-1960 (Container 27)
        - 1961-1965 (Container 27) (Box OV 2)
    - Pennsylvania Avenue, Washington, D.C. (Box OV 3)
      - Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corp.
        - Appointment, 1973 (Container 32)
      - President's Temporary Commission on Pennsylvania Avenue (Box OV 4)
        - Scrapbook, 1964-1969 (Container 39)
        - The Washington Mall Master Plan (Container 39) (Box OV 5)
  - Speeches and Writings File (Box OV 6)
    - The American Aesthetic
      - Layout (Container 47)
      - Photographic proofs (Container 47) (Box OV 7)
      - Scrapbook, 1969-1970 (Container 49) (Box OV 8)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 9)
    - Architectural drawing and diagrams (Container 56)
    - Awards and certificates (Container 56) (Box OV 10)
    - Scrapbooks (Box OV 11)
      - 1936-1969 (Container 59)
      - 1969-1970 (Container 59) (Box OV 12)